<?xml version="1.0"?> 
<opas title="Release notes">

<p>At least for now releases follow the Subversion revision numbers. Numbers in the headers show download counts for the older version.</p>


<hdr>Release 171 on 23 Nov 2009 </hdr>
<ul>
<li>fixed with severeal occupations</li>
<li>fixed bug with note texts with several chapters</li>
<li>Added to indexes multiple names, childrens and spouses parents ancestor names</li>
<li>Fixed bug with text notice not being copied from main to notice</li>
<li>Removed update to db when viewing relations notice</li>
<li>Converted unicode names to ascii by converting non ascii to x or a or o</li>
<li>Fixed javac problem with accented characters in char constants</li>
</ul>


<hdr>Release 164 on 20 Nov 2009 (2)</hdr>
<ul>
<li>Bugfixes for table duplicate links</li>

</ul>

<hdr>Release 162 on 19 Nov 2009 (3)</hdr>
<ul>
<li>Added preliminary index as excel file for descendant report.</li>

</ul>

<hdr>Release 156 on 18 Nov 2009 (4)</hdr>
<ul>
<li>Special codes like language versions and name,place lists implemented.</li>
<li>fixew bug with importing with no views</li>
<li>Added Source to relations</li>
<li>Removed unused fields from view of notices</li>
</ul>

<hdr>Release 153 on 16 Nov 2009 (2)</hdr>
<ul>
<li>Added modify and delete to name and place management to NOTE notices. Changed name array to format Surname,Givenname </li>

</ul>

<hdr>Release 144 on 15 Nov 2009 (4)</hdr>
<ul>
<li>added Add to Needle menu command</li>
<li>fixed bug with storing relations surety value</li>
</ul>

<hdr>Release 142 on 14 Nov 2009 (4)</hdr>
<ul>
<li>Added years to needle namelist. Max subjects set to 16,disable get needle if list is empty</li>
</ul>


<hdr>Release 137 on 13 Nov 2009 (7)</hdr>
<ul>
<li>Added date check. Date must be expected format to be accepted</li>
<li>removal of person to show also in relatives pane and on "needle"</li>
<li>Fixed import of refn id from Suku2004</li>
<li>Modified needle to contain several subjects in an inputDialog</li>
</ul>

<hdr>Release 132 on 12 Nov 2009 (2)</hdr>
<ul>
<li>Added correct order also to spouses childlist</li>
<li>Added checks to prevent duplicate fathers or mothers to be added by setting new parent surety value to "SomeDoubt" (40%)</li>

</ul>

<hdr>Release 129 on 11 Nov 2009 (3)</hdr>
<ul>
<li>Fixed bug that did not accept person without surname/name</li>
<li>Modified add child command to insert child in correct position if birthdates are known</li>
<li>Added automatic recognition of existing child for added spouse</li>
<li>Added request to add other parent</li>
</ul>

<hdr>Release 123 on 5 Nov 2009 (9)</hdr>
<ul>
<li>Fixed bug with "needle"</li>
<li>Modified transforming report to manage foldername with åäö. It required not to use include statements in the XSLT file.</li>

</ul>

<hdr>Release 119 on 2 Nov 2009 (10)</hdr>
<ul>
<li>Change displayorder of current sizes in Suomi Map</li>
<li>When new person is added it is shown at beginning of databasewindow.</li>

</ul>

<hdr>Release 112 on 1 Nov 2009 (5)</hdr>
<ul>
<li>Some improvements in logging.</li>
<li>Cleaning up of code</li>
<li>Changed to use image height in reports</li>
<li>Added height separately for personImage</li>
</ul>

<hdr>Release 108 on 29 Oct 2009 (12)</hdr>
<ul>
<li>Removed xml format from report formats. xml-format is now additional format with .debug trailer when debug checkbox set</li>
<li>Added optional numbering of images</li>
<li>familytree bugfix. Showd subject as parents also</li>
</ul>

<hdr>Release 97 on 28 Oct 2009 (7)</hdr>
<ul>
<li>Deleted files folder for html-report if empty. Moved stylesheet into html file so if no pictures then all in one file.</li>
<li>Added image max width for reports</li>
<li>Added Word 2003 images and image title</li>
</ul>

<hdr>Release 91 on 26 Oct 2009 (7)</hdr>
<ul>
<li>Images added to html report</li>
<li>Added max images width to report settings</li>
<li>Moved spouse print to common settings</li>
</ul>

<hdr>Release 84 on 25 Oct 2009 (6)</hdr>
<ul>
<li>XSLT 1.0 stylesheets added and code modified to call that. XSLT 2.0 was considered but the library is much larger than rest of finfamily and might make installing finfamily still more difficult. At least we start with XSLT 1.0 that comes with java.</li>
<li>Simple Html and Word xml 2003 doc implemented. Also raw xml supported at least now in the beginning. It can be used to test the stulesheets locally.</li>

</ul>

<hdr>Release 78 on 23 Oct 2009 (8)</hdr>
<ul>
<li>Added database update command to tools menu. This version requires it to be run if using databse created with older FinFamily</li>
<li>Active language variant names are in red for both notice language and relation notice language variant</li>
<li>UTF-8 texts corrected</li>
<li>Added state field. Set state and country visible when place is visible.</li>
<li>Load TypesExecl and PaikatExcel from user chosen location</li>
</ul>

<hdr>Release 72 on 22 Oct 2009 (10)</hdr>

<ul>
<li>Changed personwindow name to be same in menu and tab</li>
<li>Added headers to clipboard copy</li>
<li>New Swedish descriptions</li>
<li>Fixed excel reader to managa ÅÄÖ</li>
<li>Replaced buttons C and P witg graphic</li>
<li>Modified make subject button to have on-off position.</li>
<li>Hide relative notices when no longer active</li>
<li>Database window sorted using report language collating sequence in surname/givenname/birtdate order after query.</li>
<li>Fixed name underlining bug</li>
<li>Added opening of database draft and treeview from relatives pane</li>
<li>Added newer settings to load and store report settings</li>
</ul>

<hdr>Release 52 on 21 Oct 2009 (14)</hdr>

<ul>
<li>Changed default language to english</li>
<li>Dash before spouse in report fixed </li>
<li>Fix of Bug with "C" button (make the subject) </li>
<li>Added headers to copy-to-clipboard</li>
</ul>

<hdr>Release 47 on 20 Oct 2009 (6)</hdr>

<ul>
<li>Another fix to problem with database window sorting</li>
</ul>

<hdr>Release 45 on 20 Oct 2009</hdr>

<ul>
<li>Fixed problems with database window</li>
<li>Sorting of databaasewindow to use report language</li>
<li>Added Swedish texts</li>
<li>Close personview when database logs off</li>
</ul>

<hdr>Release 34 on 16 Oct 2009 (15)</hdr>

<ul>
<li>Added to Group and View managers alternative add subject with ancestors.</li>
<li>Swedish program texts added</li>
<li>The language texts have been moved to Properties.xls that contain macro to generate the resource budle files finfamily.property. The property files are replaced in SVN with the Excel-file but distribution has property files only. 
(This should make no difference in the application)</li>
</ul>


<hdr>Release 26 on 15 Oct 2009 (26)</hdr>

<p>Added View manager to FinFamily. Views can be used to group persons for certain uses e.g. for making copies of a 
part of teh database only that part can be identified as being the persons in the view. Views are managed 
using the database tables views and viewunits.</p>

<p>Groups is another way of grouping persons. Every person can have only one group and can be a member of several views.</p>
</opas>
