<?xml version="1.0"?> 
<opas title="Release notes">

<p>At least for now releases follow the Subversion revision numbers. Numbers in the headers show download counts for the older version. Earlier release notes are in releasenotes0172</p>

<hdr>Release 298 on 17 jan 2010</hdr>
<ul>
<li>Ancestor report improvements. Hager numbering added.</li>
<li>Gedcom import to accept also program selected dateformat.</li>
</ul>

<hdr>Release 292 on 16 jan 2010 (10)</hdr>
<ul>
<li>Ancestor report improvements. Not yet for the Espolin model.</li>

</ul>

<hdr>Release 283 on 12 jan 2010 (20)</hdr>
<ul>
<li>With Family setting implemented for ancestor report</li>
<li>Gedcom import improvements/fixes</li>
</ul>

<hdr>Release 276 on 9 jan 2010 (8)</hdr>
<ul>
<li>Ancestor report draft included</li>
</ul>

<hdr>Release 272 on 5 jan 2010 (10)</hdr>
<ul>
<li>Hiski name normalization test</li>
<li>Name type improvements in reports</li>
</ul>

<hdr>Release 266 on 5 jan 2010 (14)</hdr>
<ul>
<li>Name type fix for reports</li>
<li>Import 2004 privacy fix</li>
<li>Show hiski command fixes.</li>
<li>Only first givenname into intellisens list.</li>

</ul>


<hdr>Release 250 on 29 dec 2009 (16) </hdr>
<ul>
<li>Source window with content sensitive menu for Hiskipage added.</li>

</ul>


<hdr>Release 248 on 28 dec 2009 (4) </hdr>
<ul>
<li>Hiski import of all types to database added.</li>

</ul>

<hdr>Release 242 on 22 dec 2009 (12) </hdr>
<ul>
<li>Added textpersons to index.</li>
<li>Fixed bug with language version. Restored check of old language to suku 2004 import.</li> 
<li>Moved image before text. This enables us to write in the standard note field a bit more text for preceding image.</li>

</ul>


<hdr>Release 236 on 16 dec 2009 (14)</hdr>
<ul>
<li>gedcom import improvements</li>

</ul>


<hdr>Release 222 on 12 dec 2009 </hdr>
<ul>
<li>gedcom import implemented</li>

</ul>

<hdr>Release 209 on 9 dec 2009 </hdr>
<ul>
<li>Added gedcom import skeleton. Most of indi records are imported. Relations are not yet implemented.</li>

</ul>
<hdr>Release 190 on 5 dec 2009 (2)</hdr>
<ul>
<li>Intellisens implemented for givenname,patronyme, surname, place, noticetype, description</li>

</ul>

<hdr>Release 188 on 4 dec 2009 </hdr>
<ul>
<li>Initialized intellisens places with actual data from db at connect</li>
<li>Intellisens in use at main person place fields. press first character to display list of places. Select from list using arrowkeys and enter or mouse. Arrow keys are forwarded to scrollbar and window may scroll because of that. Searching still for solution to the scrolling efect.</li>
</ul>

<hdr>Release 184 on 2 dec 2009 </hdr>
<ul>
<li>Changed to use Metal look-and-feel if not windows</li>
<li>Fixes to problems with synchronizing person pane with the notice panes</li>
<li>Problems with synchronizing person pane with the notice panes</li>
<li>Added "intellisens" proto to main person place fields - with demo data</li>
</ul>

<hdr>Release 178 on 29 Nov 2009 </hdr>
<ul>
<li>Fixed problems with synchronizing mainpane and notices</li>
<li>Ficed problem with notice text printing</li>
</ul>

<hdr>Release 174 on 23 Nov 2009 (5)</hdr>
<ul>
<li>Reopen person with same notice at update</li>

</ul>


</opas>
