<?xml version="1.0"?> 
<opas title="Suku 11 pääpiirteet">




<p>Connect to your local database using server name <strong>localhost</strong> and fill in the database and the user and password you have created. Press OK to login.</p>

<hdr>Starting the database.</hdr>

<p>Depending on the database configuration you may need to start it before use if login fails. The preferred way is to restart the database using the command that were installed with the database. Below commands should work on one of the postgers builds available by giving the two commands after each other.:

<ul>
<li>Tools - Stop PostgreSQL</li>
<li>Tools - Start PostgreSQL</li>
</ul>

</p>





<hdr>Commands on the File-menu</hdr>
<p><image src="sukufile.jpg" border="0"  alt=""/></p> 

<p>
<ul>
<li><link lref="suku10imp">Import Suku 2004 backup</link>. Use this command to import the file kennedy.xml.gz. The file is located in the file kennedy.zip at the sourceforge server. The file is a backup file from the previous version of the application (Sukuohjelmisto 2004).</li>
<li>The command <strong>Create new database</strong> created a new database structure in the database you have opened. At this development phase there is no check against this and you should understand that the command deleted all data from your database. The database is initialized with the command in finfamily.sql that you find inside suku.jar. You can open suku.jar as a zip-file.</li>
<li>Print the person, Open text and Save text are there for developer use only. You may experiment with them if you like.</li>
<li>Show on map create a map of Finland with locations of your finnish relatives. The same functinality is done using the button <image src="showmap.jpg" border="0" type="inline" title="" /></li>
</ul>
</p>


<hdr>Query database</hdr>

<p>Use File - Query database command or the <image src="query.jpg" border="0" type="inline" title="" /> button to fetch paerons from your database. </p>

<p><image src="dbquery.jpg" border="0" title="Suku 11 login" alt=""/></p> 

<p>The Search arguments lets you restrict your search and the columns to show on the result. The columns in the result you select in the group on the right and the search argumnets in the main area of the window. Reset button removes all search arguments and OK starts the search. With no search arguments all persons in your database will be shown.</p>


<hdr>Databasewindow</hdr>

<p>The program screen is divided in two sides. The left side is reserved for the database view. The right side is used for a few other screens. Some windowses are opened in separate dialogs or windowses.</p>

<p><image src="dbview.jpg" border="0" alt=""/></p> 

<p>Sort the database window by pressing one of the column headers.</p>


</opas>