<?xml version="1.0"?> 
<opas title="FinFamily Main features">

<p>The Finfamily installation is done by downloading the zipfile finfamilyxxxx.zip from the SourceForge server at
<link href="https://sourceforge.net/projects/finfamily/"/>. Download the latest program version from there. You may also download some auxiliary files such as the small database backup file kennedy.zip to test the application.</p>

<p>To use the application source you should do following (or similar)

<ul>
<li>If you don't have <link href="http://java.sun.com">Java 1.6 SDK</link> install it</li>
<li>Do Checkout with (Tortoise SVN) to an empty folder using url <strong>https://finfamily.svn.sourceforge.net/svnroot/finfamily/trunk</strong></li>
<li>You can build the application using the buildit.bat command or similar. This requires 
that you have installed <link href="http://ant.apache.org">Ant software</link> and the required environment variable ANT_HOME</li>
<li>You can run the application on a IDE of your choise. The settings are ready for the Eclipse IDE but other IDE should work too. Set the VM arguments in Eclipse as -Xms64m -Xmx500m -Djava.util.logging.config.file=properties/logging.properties. It's about the same as in suku.sh</li>
</ul> 
</p> 


<p>A guide in Finnish is available at <link href="http://www.sukuohjelmisto.fi/suku11"/>. I try to keep both guides updated but don't guarantee it.</p>

<p>To run FinFamily you must have installed java 1.6 on your workstation and you need tcp/ip access to a PostgreSQL database. 
Usually this means you must also install the PostgreSQL server on your workstation. You'll find java on 
<link href="http://java.sun.com"/> adn PostgreSQL on <link href="http://www.postgresql.org"/>.</p>

<p>You need to create an useraccount and database to the PostgreSQL server. You can do that using the tool pgAdmin that you may have installed if you installed your database on your windows workstation. On other systems you may need to use the text-mode commands of PostgreSQL server.</p>

<p>Unzip the zipfile to a directory of your choice such as My Documents\finfamily. If you are running on a windows workstation start FinFamily by starting Suku.exe. On other systems you should start it by executing the scriptfile suku.sh.'
The first thing the program does is to open the login screen.</p>

<p><image src="sukulogin.jpg" border="0"  alt=""/></p> 

<p>You would see when you logion to the database next time a list of available databses and the userid /password you used previousl. There is a simple <link lref="dbadmin">Database admin functionality</link> for adding standard users and databases to your local postgreSQL server.</p>


</opas>
